# PARTH BHAVESH KUMAR BHATT

6084 Stanton Dr SW, Edmonton, Alberta, T6X 0Z4 | (705) 791-4648 parthkumar9@outlook.com | https://parthbio.vercel.app/

# **Summary**

I bring over 2 years of valuable IT experience focused on maintaining and enhancing web-based applications through the entire Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC). My skill set is underpinned by a deep understanding of Object-Oriented Programming(OOP), Database Programming, E-commerce, and Software Development best practices. I am dedicated to delivering high-quality solutions on schedule, a commitment honed during my earlier career in Project Coordinator roles.

### **Technical Expertise**

- Backend Skills: Node JS, Python, Django, Pandas, Express. JS, Vite JS
- Frontend / Scripting Skills: HTML, CSS, JAVA Script, React JS, Angular JS, Vue JS Gatsby JS, FramerMotion, JSON, Tailwind CSS
- Database Skills: MySql, PostgreSQL, MongoDb, Firestore, Graphql
- Cloud / DevOps Skills : Aws Cloud, GIT, GitHub, Github Actions, Vercel
- Software Testing Tools: Mocha, Chai, Cypress, Selenium IDE (Web Application Testing)
- **Development Tools**: Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ IDEA, Wordpress, Magento 2.4, Putty, Sanity.io, Postman, MySql work bench SQL developer,

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Full-stack Developer / Project Manager

VebCommerce, Alberta, CA (July 2022 - August 2023)

VebCommerce, a SAAS Web platform that allows endless integration of e-commerce platforms such as Amazon, eBay, Magento, Shopify & more. Developed to be a one-stop destination & complete automation for all e-commerce sellers.

- Understand business's strategic direction, goals and objectives and deliver the program successfully along those goals and objectives.
- Independently developed numerous end-to-end modules, encompassing data modeling, business logic, **RESTful APIs**, and frontend components.
- Responsible for generating and distributing Daily Status, Weekly Status and Exit Summary Reports
- Participate in **Agile** Development methodology of solutions based on acceptance criteria and design to drive the software development process effectively.
- Trace user stories to business objectives and the **product vision** throughout the sprint to ensure it's actually been delivered as imagined.
- Developed dynamic, responsive, and interactive front-end components using **AngularJS**. This involve creating reusable components, directives, controllers, and services.

#### **Web Developer**

Lofcart Alberta Ltd, Alberta, CA (Jan 2021 - June 2022)

Web Developer in the team responsible for integrations and developer tools. I was in charge of defining and improving the website which Lofcart.com was running as per business requirements.

- Redesigned existing frontend website architecture to include new features.
- Providing maintenance and support for **Magento 2** Migration, Upgradation, plugin development and updating security patches.
- Designed custom user interactions on Lofcart's web admin panel with inherent features that optimized user journeys and drove a **25% decrease** in bounce rates..
- Developed dynamic Landing pages using frameworks like NextJS and GatsbyJs with CMS tools like Sanity.io and GraphQI.
- Setup CI/CD Pipeline using DevOps tools such as GIT, GitHub.
- Collaborated within an **Agile** development framework, actively engaging in numerous Scrum meetings to drive the software development process effectively.

# **Bantsy-Al Saas Platform**

Alberta, CA (Personal Project)

- Developed frontend dashboard and landing page using ReactJS, TailwindCSS, ShadcnUI.
- Implemented user authentication and profile with **CLERK**.
- Developed back-end using **NextJS(App router)** with website applications.
- Created 4 AI Saas tools leveraging **OpenAI** developer APIs.
- Maintained all platform databases using MySql & MongoDb
- Ensured fast customer support by integrating **CRISP**.
- Ensured free, subscription & paywall model with **Stripe**.

#### **Discord Clone**

Alberta,CA (Personal Project)

- Server creation and customization, Infinite loading for messages in batches of 10 (tanstack/query)
- 1:1 realtime conversation & calls between members implemented using Socket.io
- Unique invite link generation & invite system plus user management (Kick, Role change Guest / Moderator)
- Light / Dark mode, Full responsivity and mobile UI
- ORM using Prisma and MySQL database using Planetscale
- Implemented user authentication and profile with CLERK.

### **Education**

Computer Programmer, Diploma Program, Co-op

September 2018- May 2021

Georgian College, Barrie, ON

### Certifications

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Sept 2023

Smartphone Repair Master technician
 Oct 2021

SafeTALK
 Sep 2019

•	Communicate continuously and effectively with external business partners and internal teams to articulate a project's comprehensive requirements.  Identify gaps in data requirements between as-is and to be states. Model the data requirements to ensure that the data will support the new solution.
	My expertise spans a wide array of programming languages, libraries, and frameworks, such as React.js, Angular.js, Gatsby.js, and Framer Motion, as well as back-end development with Node.js and Python.